Why didn't you go after Jonas?
If I had left this spot,
you would have been consumed
by the wolves. That.
It would have been worth it
if we would have stopped him.
But now you've protected me so.
That nothing would happen
to your other
wing.
That's the reason, isn't it?
I know I'm not
capable of commanding you.
I understand that. I just wish.
Jonas. Why?
So he could win the contest.
He stole your mother's
design so that he could
copy them,
but he lacked the skill.
So he made a plan
to take your work instead.
And now he said it to Lewiston.
This is the silver
sugar that we're missing.
Cathy is able
to become invisible. I am sure
she was the one who stole it.
Then Jonas guessed
how much sugar you
would use to make your piece.
He very discreetly moved
that amount into
your cargo hold ahead of time,
and took off in your wagon
along with your work inside.
How can you know all that? That's
the way humans behave here.
The exhibition's in two days.
Jonas will have
already gotten
to Lewiston by then.
It's too late now.
You're all right with that?
Of course I'm not.
Even if I have you with me,
there's nothing I can do
to change things now.
I might as well set you free.
Now get out of here.
So alone again.
I'm sorry, mama.
My dream was to become
a silver sugar master
and send your
spirit to the heavens
on full Sol day.
And now it will come true.
Mama. Mama!
Why do you have to die? Why
did you leave me here by myself?
My mama. Why?
Beautiful.
You must be a human.
You're the one
who allowed me to be boring.
Yes.
You know how
fairies are born when
human eyes cause an object's
energy to condense like that.
So you're the same as me.
My name is.
Le Soleil mean?
Go forth and be free.
Steer clear of humans.
They capture us and force
us to serve their will.
They're monsters.
Is that true?
But what about this young lady?
She's human. She's
a rare exception. Now be gone.
Find a place where you'll
be safe and stay there.
How kind you are. Thank you.
What is that face for? It's
just I gave you your wing back.
So why are you still here?
Because you haven't
fulfilled your promise to me.
And I can't leave until
you do it. What promise?
Don't you remember?
I want my sugar confection.
Oh, yes. Of course.
Go ahead, make me one.
I'll be waiting.
Right. I have to keep my words,
don't I?
I'll make something
incredible for you.
Wait. You're much too
filthy to work with food.
Wear this. It was in the cargo
hold. I doubt he'll mind. My.
I'll make something great.
Herschel.
Even if I can't
go to the exhibition.
Even if he leaves again
after I give it to him.
This is for shell,
who chose to come back to me.
For him. I'll make something
that I think is truly beautiful.
So.
I'm done.
But.
I know that it's tiny,
but this candy
comes from my heart.
It is my finest work.
Beautiful.
Thank you. Shel.
Will you accept it?
Do you mind
if I touch your wing?
Go ahead. Are you sure? Mm.
It feels warm.
Are you satisfied? Yes. This confection.
It's mine. Correct? Yes.
Well, then I'll do
as I please with it.
Shall get. On. Time to go.
Go where? Lewiston.
Ride through the night.
We'll arrive in the morning.
You need to become a silver sugar
master this year, right? Huh?
Well, yes, but I don't
have my entry anymore.
Use this. Huh?
You said yourself that
it was your finest work, remember?
Don't accept defeat
unless you fail.
Why are you doing this for me?
You gave me back my wing.
So you're not my master anymore.
And that means we can be
friends. If you so desire.
Really? Shell do you want to?
We'll see.
Huh? It'll be dark soon.
Do you think we can get past
the bloody highway safely?
Who do you
think you're traveling with?
I wonder which school
is going to
win this year. Mercury for sure.
The page school is good.
What? Not recently.
I'm rooting
for the Radclyffe School.
His Majesty King Edmund
the Second has arrived.
What's that? Look out! Huh?
Out of the way. Who are they?
I came here for the.
Exhibition and
I see that the results have not.
Been declared yet. Dan.
Please let me enter too.
But I'm not affiliated with any
school. My name. You there.
Stop! Please let me through.
Well well, well.
I didn't think you'd be here.
And now
you're making a grand entrance,
old Hugh.
Mercury,
are you familiar with this girl?
Yes, sir. And she is indeed a
sugar artisan. She's Hugh Mercury.
The head of the Mercury
Workshop school
and the current
silver sugar Viscount.
Very well. Since you can attest to
her talent, she may participate.
Thank you very much.
Hello, Ann. You don't look
half bad wearing my clothes.
And would you look at that?
You've
entered a creation that's
barely large enough
to be a snack for a small child.
I'm honestly impressed
that you have the nerve.
You know a lot about nerve,
don't you?
Claiming someone else's
work as your own.
That is a shameless as it gets.
I have no idea what you mean.
It's time for the sugar
confectionery exhibition.
Today we will
decide the greatest sugar
artisan in the land
and grant them
the title
of Silver Sugar Master.
It's begun. Each confection will
now be judged by His Majesty.
It's such a huge nose.
To bring them closer, right.
Jonas Sanders and Anne Halford,
please bring
your sugar confections
forward for viewing.
I'm at quite a loss.
Look, Mercury.
This is odd. To my eye, these
pieces have an
eerily similar beauty.
Indeed they do.
Given how alike they are,
it almost appears as though
they were crafted
by the same artisan, doesn't it?
Well, sire.
Which one of them do you prefer?
I like this a great deal.
It seems ephemeral, as though
it might shatter at any instant
and yet so full of life.
In all my days I've never
seen such a beautiful peace.
Yes, that sugar confection
certainly is magnificent.
But we must remember one thing.
It's
meant to be a centerpiece
for the festival.
The winning piece must be
large and spectacular.
This one is lovely, but we can't
be sure that her skills would
be suited to a bigger creation.
Yes, that's a fair point.
Very well.
In that case.
Subjects, I am pleased
to award this year's
Royal Medal to
the piece made by Jonas Anders.
Stand aside and. Helford.
You may now approach Youngman.
At this time,
His Majesty will examine
the three barrels of silver
sugar that you have refined,
so that you may present
them along with your work.
It's amazing.
Where'd you come from? What
is the meaning of this, Anders?
An entire barrel's worth
of silver sugar is missing.
But that's impossible.
Oh, please forgive me,
my king, for I am not
but a simple labor fairy who.
Must do the bidding of my master,
Jonas Anders, at all costs.
He's so incompetent
and silver sugar making
that he couldn't produce
the amount you required.
That's why he ordered me to hide
in the barrel
and use my illusory
magic to make it appear full.
What is my girl doing here?
The thought of.
Deceiving you, Your Majesty. Did
he eat all that silver sugar?
It's not true. Come here.
Ouch! The truth is,
this fairy doesn't work for me.
He actually belongs
to Anne Halford. She ordered
him to sneak into
that barrel to cheat
her way into becoming
the next silver sugar master.
Hey! Hands off of Anne! See?
He's
so familiar with her.
They're in this together.
It is true that this fairy
and I know each other.
That said, I still don't
know why he did such a thing.
Does the reason make
any difference? You have
to tell these people
the truth and.
Tell them what
this lowlife did to you.
You're right, I will.
On our way.
Here, he deceived me, rode
away with my sugar confection.
So he could enter
it as his thinking
no one would know.
These are both my work.
And this fairy knew that. So he.
No. That's an egregious lie.
Let go of her! Get off me!
You keep on lying.
I'm not. You're the liar here.
Perhaps we should have them prove
themselves. Your thoughts. Majesty.
Oh, you know, a way to confirm
which of them is responsible
for creating
these confections? If so,
then please proceed.
Yes, sir. All right.
I'll give you
the same test I gave
you when we first met.
Except I'll select the motif.
Yes. The focus
of the piece that was chosen
are these butterflies.
Recreate them exactly.
While His Majesty bears witness.
And we'll know who
the real creator is.
Are we clear? Perfectly.
Thank you. Jonas. Well, begin.
I sense it.
Shall stayed here to watch me.
I'll create a wonderful
butterfly, one that will make
shell happy the best
he's ever seen.
Wings need to be lustrous.
Yes, just like his wings are.
I'll make them beautiful.
That's enough.
Are. His butterfly isn't
even worth discussing.
No,
this only happened because I was
way too distracted and rushed
to perform at my best.
If I had a quiet place to work
by myself and a little more
time, then I a disgraced Jonas.
Alfred's butterfly does
bear resemblance to the
chosen entry.
But it is different.
I'm afraid I don't
understand you. Based on these,
it seems obvious who
the true creator must have been.
Is there some sort
of problem with the pieces?
Well, sire,
between this one and the
ones on the display you chose,
which butterfly do you
like the best? Hmm?
Harford's butterfly
is superior by far,
it is even more impressive
than the one I had.
I see. You're right. Mercury. They
clearly aren't the same, right?
So I can't declare
the answer with any certainty.
Hmm'hmm. Therefore, whoever
crafted the confection that
I chose must
not be present today.
Downing. So this year
the Royal Medal goes to no one.
What did he say?
No one gets the medal.
Does that mean no one
becomes a silver
sugar master? That was a shame.
Silver sugar. Viscount.
Oh, no. That's not
be so formal. Just call me Hugh.
You. What happened? You
must have known it was my work.
So why did you
act like you didn't?
It wasn't. Both of us heard
what the king said. But still.
Improving your skills worked against you. This
butterfly you made just now.
It wasn't you imitating somebody else. This
is clearly your original work.
Did you hear that, mama?
Did you see it?
Miss Anne Halford. The Queen
asked me to tell you something.
Yes. She hopes
you'll return next year
with another piece that's
worthy of the festival.
She'll be looking
forward to seeing it.
Yes, sir. Of course. I promise
I will be back next year.
Mercury,
punish Anders as you see fit.
What do you think, Anne? You're the
person he wronged, after all.
Stand up, Jonas. Right now.
There. I knew I'd feel
better if I could give
him a good slap in the face.
Very direct.
I like the way you think.
Well, hell,
I suppose we're done here.
Sorry. Excuse me. Pardon me. Oh.
Thank you. Shall.
I wanted to be a silver sugar
master so I could make
mama proud
when I sent her to the heavens.
Despite everything, I failed.
So mama will have
to be content
with the best sugar
confection I can make right now.
Next year. No matter what,
I'll come here again.
Anyway, I promise the sugar confection to
you. Remember? Please take it.
It looks awful. Awful.
I wanted a truly
delicious piece made by a
genuine silver sugar master.
What's wrong with you?
So it's not
good enough now?
I told you, I'm not.
A silver sugar master just yet.
But
I know I'll get it next year.
Then I'll have it in a year.
I don't need it till then.
Until you
achieve that title.
I'll wait by your side.
Are you sure? And did he just.
For the first time.
He used my name.
What did you think of my
brilliant award winning acting work?
Oh, mithril. I'm really sorry.
I never
should have suspected that you
had eaten my silver sugar,
even for a second. Don't worry.
About it. I know that's just
the way you humans operate.
And I told you my full
name is Mithril Lid Pod.
Then tell me something.
Mithril lid pod.
How did you figure out that Jonas
had stolen my sugar confection?
Have you been following us
the entire time? Huh?
No. I went back to your
cart after you accused me.
Huh? I was upset,
so I went to bed in a huff.
And when I woke up,
Jonas had taken the car.
Oh, so that's what happened. How
long were you asleep, anyway?
Listen,
the important thing is that I'm
going to repay my debt to you,
no matter how stubborn
I have to be.
I said I'd follow you
into the underworld. Right.
Mr. Lidford,
do you know what I mean
when I say that you are
a helpful nuisance?
No, I don't, sorry.
And by the way,
why are you still traveling
with an scarecrow?
Promised to give me something.
Wait, I'm Scarecrow again.
But you used
my real name earlier.
Hurry on up, Scarecrow.
Get in the cart.
Fine. I suppose I'll let it pass
this time, but. Name is Ian.
Let's go. Are you going
to drive? That's right.
That's just the mood I'm in.